let's look at the solution to a raspful
quiz so the question was is it better to
not push anything anymore once the rice
is full or simply wrap around and keep
overwriting all the dresses with new
ones it turns out that the wraparound
approach is much better than the don't
push approach to see why keep in mind
that our program will look like this
we have the main function
it executes for a while then calls some
other function
this results in pushing something onto
the rest our high level function here
will do a lot of work occasionally
calling
other functions
and so on we push to see
what happens here without running out of
space let's say that our ass only has
two entries the first entry will be
consumed by pushing
the return address when main calls do it
the second one will be consumed when we
call the function func from do it
at this point
we're calling the function do less
and it might call for example the add
function many many times so we're
getting to the place where functions are
really small and ideally we would you
know push each time and then pop when we
return and so on if we only have one
entry then really our entire res will be
used just when we call do it and
as long as we stay and do it which might
be a very large function because it
might be doing most of the actual work
in the program
all of the function calls that we are
doing really end up being mispredicted
because we ran out of raw space and the
one time that we will have a correct
prediction is when we finally return
from do it if we have two entries a
similar thing will happen we will
consume the first entry by basically
pushing the first thing so pretty much
we're kind of using an entry here just
to save one misprediction at the final
return
here again we are using the second entry
just to save the return from func
whenever that happens and func itself
could be calling a lot of functions so
the don't push approach basically
spending entries
on kind of long-term things that need to
be remembered
so that we can finally save a
misprediction once we reach the return
point from the large function in
contrast the wrap around approach
is gonna
push this push this
push this thus overwriting this entry so
now what we are doing is we are
basically gonna be correctly predicting
calls to small functions and returns and
we can have many of those
in return for inaccurately predicting
the final returns from large functions
because we have many more small function
calls than large function calls
in the end we are more effectively using
the few entries we have pretty much here
we are kind of using the entry to save
a misprediction over a very short period
of time thus this entry gets utilized
and then released very quickly whereas
here we are using an entry for a long
time to save a single misprediction and
in the end we want to save as many
mispredictions as we can so that's why
the wraparound approach works better
because it ends up correctly predicting
calls to small functions
many of which we can have in return for
not correctly predicting the return
from large functions to main etc
another thing to keep in mind with the
res is that it is a predictor so
either way we will be having some
mispredictions we are allowed to have
mispredictions all that will happen is
that there will be a branch
misprediction basically we will fetch
the wrong instructions and have to
recover from that
so in the end the discussion about what
to do with the ras has to do with
achieving a larger number of correct
predictions
but neither of these two ways can
actually do things perfectly so in the
end we need to just choose which one
gives us more correct predictions and it
turns out that the wraparound approach
predicts better than the don't push
approach while both of them result in
mispredictions anyway